前情提要
德怀特·曼菲雷迪
STACY: Dwight Manfredi.
他在甲壳虫乐队唱红之前
I got a rap sheet in front of me.
就有犯罪记录了
Goes back to before the Beatles.
他请我喝了一杯 我俩啥都没干
He bought me a drink. Nothing happened.
我是烟酒火器管理局的特工
I'm an ATF agent.
你的照片传到了我办公室
Your picture came through my office.
去哪儿 老大
Where to, boss?
你应该去上大学
MARK: You should be in college.
他是个商人 跟着他我受益匪浅
Dude a businessman. I can learn a lot from.
既能赚到钱
DWIGHT: We'll be making money
联调局也奈何不了我们
and the feds won't be able to touch it.
我需要看证件 这个1998年就过期了
Need to see some ID. This expired in 1998.
这是实习司机许可
That's the learners permit.
大麻农场多了去了
There's other weed farms.
你价格得再降点 吉米
You got to do better on the price, Jimmy.
前十个单位1200 之后的750
1200 for the first ten units and 750 after that.
等我吃下饼干 提议就撤回
The offer expires when I swallow this cracker.
你挺会讨价还价啊
You drive a hard bargain.
跟他们的事
The thing with them.
你得把矛盾处理好
You gotta make this right.
十万应该能够了
A hundred grand would do it.
你的家人对你来塔尔萨怎么看
What does your family think about you being here?
-你女儿  -蒂娜
- Your daughter. - Tina.
是他 那个神经病
MAN: It's him. The psycho.
来杀我了 我想找个朋友
Here's here to kill me. I'm looking for a friend.
梅奥酒店
他应该住在你们酒店
I believe he's staying at your hotel.
哦 纽约来的曼先生 对吧
Oh, Mr. Man. From New York, right?
就是他
ARMAND: That's him.
一名警官中枪
POLICE OFFICER: We have an officer shot.
目前情况稳定
Condition currently stable.
救护车正送往塔尔萨总医院
Ambulance en route to Tulsa General.
嫌犯已被围困 周边安全
Suspect is barricaded. Perimeter is secure.
确认收到
POLICE OFFICER 2: Copy that. 10-4.
杜蒙特先生
Mr. Dumont,
现在是你和平投降的机会
I'm giving you the opportunity to surrender peacefully.
只要你配合 我们保证不伤害你
If you comply, I guarantee you will not be harmed.
滚出我的土地
Get off my fucking property!
这不是你的土地 杜蒙特先生
This is not your property, Mr. Dumont.
去死吧
DUMONT: Fuck you.
提示装甲部队
Cue the cavalry.
-别激动 老杜  -基尔
- Easy, Dumont! - Keel!
是你吗
That you?
你能和他谈谈吗
Can you talk to him?
听上去他立场很坚定
Sounds to me like his position is pretty clear.
你要是帮不了忙
What the fuck are you doing here
那他妈来干什么
if you're not going to help?
当目击证人
Eh, witness.
把他带出去
Get him the fuck out of here.
他们让你没得选 杜蒙特
They left you no choice Dumont.
让我把狗子放出去
I'm letting my dogs out.
别伤害他们
Don't hurt them.
都是乖孩子
They're good boys.
一手放窗外 一手握在方向盘
♪ One out the window and one on the wheel ♪
蓝天下的州际公路一望无际
♪ Open interstate and sky full of blue skies ♪
那种自由的感觉
♪ Just somethin' 'bout the way that freedom feels ♪
白色的尖桩栅栏 小镇水箱
♪ White picket fence, water tank town... ♪
-那是老派洛特  -是啊 我见过他
- That's old Pilot. - Yeah, I've seen him around.
他的家大概在一英里之外
WAITRESS: Lives about a mile from here.
马场的人也不管管吗
They just let him walk around like that?
管不住啊
WAITRESS: That's all him.
不是所有马儿都能被圈养
You know, not all horses are a fan of the pasture.
可不是嘛
Tell me about it.
你是真爱听老歌啊
TYSON: Do you really like this old stuff?
超爱
DWIGHT: Love it.
下一个路口左转
Make that next left over there,
别忘了打手势
don't forget your hand signal either.
早就没人这么做了
No one does that anymore--
想通过路考就必须打
Not unless they want to pass the road test.
我在想走条捷径
♪ I was thinkin' 'bout a shortcut I could take ♪
但我似乎犯了一个错误
♪ But it seems like I made a mistake ♪
需要我来开吗
TYSON: You want me to drive?
-我能行  -你确定
- I got it. - You sure?
我不介意来开车
I don't mind driving.
你当然不介意 我钱给到位了
Oh, you shouldn't mind. I pay you enough.
-正想提这事呢  -不会吧
- About that, uh-- - Hey.
你不会这么快就
I know you don't have the balls
斗胆要求加薪吧
to be asking me for a raise this soon.
好吧 那我问你
All right, well, let me ask you this.
你觉得我五年之后会做什么
Where you see me in the next five years?
高速公路也许不是好选择
♪ The expressway is not the best way ♪
凌晨五点就拥堵不堪
♪ At five o'clock it's much too crowded ♪
-我觉得  -之后会怎样
- Where do I-- - See me?
对 五年之后
Yeah. Five years.
你知道我是个罪犯吧
You realize I'm a criminal, right?
我上网查过 把你摸得门清
I got Google, man. I know all about you.
那你自己觉得呢
Where do you see you
自己5年之后会做什么
in five years?
应该是身居高位手握权力吧 比如 帮派首领
Like a position of power or something, like a-- a capo?
-你当不了首领  -因为我不是意大利人
- You can't be a capo. - Oh, 'cause I'm not Italian?
没错 外加其他原因
Ye-- that and beyond that.
其他原因 什么 为什么
"Beyond that." What? What? Why?
听着 孩子
Listen kid.
你虽不是循规蹈矩的童子军
You're not a boy scout,
但也不是坏人
but you're not a bad guy either.
你懂我意思吗
You know what I'm saying?
来 你来开吧
Come on, you drive.
反正你开得比我好
You're a better driver anyway.
BGM: "MVP" by Wiz Khalifa
猜猜谁又带着一卷好货
♪ Guess who's back in the motherfucking house ♪
钻进了屋子里
♪ With a big fat joint ♪
女孩都朝我涌来 让我应接不暇
♪ Girls get close, rub me in my ointment ♪
女孩对我频送秋波 我得一个一个来
♪ So many chicks, gotta make an appointment ♪
她的朋友呼朋引伴
♪ So many dips all her friends wanna join in ♪
生活才不无聊 跟男友分手吧
♪ Life ain't boring, broke up with boyfriend ♪
这是干嘛 低配版的伍德斯托克音乐节吗
What's this, a cut-rate Woodstock?
伍德斯托克音乐节 上世纪60-70年代的音乐节
-伍德斯托克音乐节是啥  -伍德斯托克都不知道 天
- What's Woodstock? - "What's Woodstock?" Jesus.
请你闭嘴行吗
MAN: Will you shut the fuck up?
不用付房租 住在仓库里
♪ Live rent free in my mind that's storage ♪
叶子多到爆 看起来像森林
♪ Whole lotta tree, it look like a forest ♪
你不想做爱
♪ You don't wanna fuck ♪
请自己出去
♪ You know right where the door is ♪
-好恶心  -纯粹是胡扯
- GIRL: Gross. - No different from baloney.
我也不会吃这玩意
I wouldn't eat that either.
停在卡车上 全白是我的幸运色
♪ Pull up in a truck, all white that's a fortune ♪
年度最佳球员 没错 我名至实归
♪ Player of the Year, that's right I'm awarded ♪
最佳球员 没错就是我
♪ MVP, baby, that be me ♪
别人靠付钱 但老子靠刷脸
♪ Some might pay, but I get mines free ♪
这游戏我才是老大
♪ I run G-A-M-E ♪
比利 这里还有笑气 哥们儿
Billy! They got nitrous, dude!
-这家伙干趴了  -行吧
- Man down. - Word.
我去那边拿瓶啤酒
I'mma run over here, get a beer.
你从他那什么也得不到
♪ You can't get nothing from him ♪
没人能做到
♪ No can do ♪
你什么都得不到 没人能得到
♪ You can't get nothing, no, no can do ♪
来两瓶 两瓶啤酒
Can I get two? Two beers?
-你来了  -我给你带了瓶巴罗洛
- You made it. - Yeah, I got you some Barolo.
巴罗洛葡萄酒吗
- Barolo? - Mm-hmm.
谢谢 你没必要带的
Thanks. You didn't have to do that.
现在知道了
I can see that now.
-你还记得格蕾丝吗  -记得 你好格蕾丝
- You remember Grace? - I do. How you doing Grace?
无意冒犯 但我特别敏感易激
No offense, but I get triggered pretty easily.
什么 叫敏感易激
What's "triggered?"
易激
Triggered.
就是你那天用水杯砸了弗雷德啊
The other day when you hit Fred with the water bottle.
抱歉 今后一定注意
Sorry, I'll be more careful.
小姑娘真脆弱
- A little fragile. - Ha.
你听到消息了吗
Did you see?
联调局突袭了斯特沃特的那家药房
The Feds raided that dispensary at Stillwater?
你该感恩有我
You're lucky I came around.
-是啊 我的德怀特大恩人  -算你聪明
- Yeah, my Dwight Knight. - Yeah? Wise guy.
-他是什么情况  -呃 该死
- What's his story? - Oh, shit.
嘿 克林特
Hey, Clint!
你能带他去医院吗
Will you take him to Hillcrest?
-气球里装的是什么  -N20
- What's in that balloon? - N2O.
-一氧化二氮  -一个笑气气球卖5刀
- Nitrous oxide. - $5 a pop for laughing gas?
在奥拉拉之地 他们一个卖十块呢
They sell it for ten at Ogallala-Land.
什么 什么地方
Wha-- la- what land?
奥拉拉之地 是个音乐节
Ogallala-Land. It's a music festival.
他们是谁
And who are they?
他们
They are, um...
跟我们不一样
different.
做笑气生意的那群人
- Mm-hmm. - BODHI: The nitrous guys.
跟我们不是一个圈子的
They're not really a part of the community.
-嘿  -还好吗
- Hey. - What's going on?
谢谢
DWIGHT: Thanks.
我问你个问题
Let me ask you something.
这一瓶气
How many balloons
能吹多少个气球
do you think you get out of one of the tanks?
350个 咋了
350. Why?
我喜欢数字
I like numbers.
你知道一氧化二氮吗 了解多少
What do you know about nitrous oxide?
派对上用的
Party drug.
我之前问过一小子
DWIGHT: I was talking to this kid.
他说一瓶笑气
He says one of those tanks
能吹350个气球 一个卖10刀
makes about 350 balloons at $10 a pop.
他还说很快会有一个音乐节
He also said there's this concert coming to town,
名字怪兮兮的 叫
something with a crazy name.
-奥拉拉之地音乐节  -对
- Ogallala-Land Festival. - DWIGHT: Right.
假设我们搞10瓶过去
Now, let's just say you got ten tanks there,
连卖三个晚上 一个气球收1O刀
three nights, $10 a pop.
-那就是10万多的样子  -是啊
- It's a little over 100 grand. - That's right.
所以我要怎么帮上忙
So, how do I figure in all this?
你这里严格说来是家餐厅 对吧
Technically, this is a restaurant, right?
有待商榷 但从技术上讲是
That's debatable, but yeah, technically,
所以你可以大量购买笑气
So you can buy nitrous in bulk.
假设哈 你们餐厅突然需要大量鲜奶油
Like, if you had a sudden need for a ton of whipped cream,
鲜奶油需要笑气打发 用笑气在喷射出后 可以更好的定型和保持形状
你这么一说 我可能还真需要
Come to think of it, I just might.
大日子啊 感觉怎么样
It's a big day today. How you feeling?
-你感觉怎么样  -那还用问吗
- How you feeling? - DWIGHT: You kidding?
等我拿到驾照
When I get my license,
可以随时载大美女
I'll be able to take pretty Peggy Sue
去看露天电影了
to the drive-in.
你在想什么呢
What's on your mind?
好吧 你可能觉得我在开玩笑
Okay, I know you think it's some type of joke
不过 你看过电影《好家伙》吗
or something, but you seen Goodfellas?
《好家伙》是一部1990年的美国黑帮犯罪电影 由导演马丁·斯科塞斯执导
雷·里奥塔只有一半意大利血统
Ray Liotta, he was only half Italian,
但他也在黑帮混的风生水起
but he was still in the thick of that shit.
他也算个高层吧
So, he was, like, a high level associate, right?
我五年后也能变成那样
I can be like that in five years.
那你知道亨利·希尔 雷·里奥塔演得那个角色
You realize Henry Hill, Ray Liotta's character,
差点就被人干掉了吗
came that close to getting whacked?
不光是他 还有他家人
Him and his family.
好吧 那种低级错误我不会犯的
Okay, well, I wouldn't do that dumb shit,
我会很聪明的
you know, I'd be smart about it.
想变聪明吗 就去上大学
Wanna be smart? Go to college.
试过了 不适合我
I already tried that and it's not for me.
课程表 教学大纲 绩点什么的
Schedules, your curriculum, grades and all of that.
-这才是重点  -什么意思
- That's the whole point. - What is?
你觉得真有人关心
Do you think anyone really gives a shit
你念了什么专业吗
about what your major is?
英国文学还是生物 无所谓
English literature, biology, whatever.
大学学历的意义
The whole point of a college degree
在于告诉用人单位
is to show a potential employer
你能够连续四年坚持不懈
that you showed up someplace four years in a row,
以较好的成绩完成一系列任务
completed a series of tasks reasonably well,
并且是按时完成
and on time.
好让他知道
So if he hires you,
如果雇了你 你大概率
there's a semi-decent chance
会每天准时来上班
that you'll show up there every day
不会搞砸他生意
and not fuck his business up.
你觉得这就是大学的意义
That's what you think college is about?
对 此外还包括喝啤酒和上床
That, drinking beer and getting laid.
这些家伙还是老样子
These guys never change.
-早啊  -早上好
- PAUL: Morning. - Good morning.
我是保罗·奇弗斯
- I'm Paul Cheevers. - Mm-hmm.
今天我负责你的路考 曼菲雷迪先生
I'll be administering your test Mr. Manfredi.
叫我德怀特就行
No, call me Dwight.
-好的 德怀特  -好的 保罗
- Okay, Dwight. - Okay, Paul.
如果你准备好了
Well, if you're ready...
就把车开出来 然后左转
let's have you pull out and make a left.
卧槽 该死
Fuck. Goddamnit.
好久不开了
Been a while.
就把车开出来 左转
PAUL: So just pull out and make a left
咱们从这里开始
that's where we are going to start off,
先左转 好的
just make a left, okay.
所以你是新手司机吗
So, you a new driver?
不 开什么玩笑 我都开了一辈子车了
Nah, you kidding? I've been driving my whole life,
我刚从纽约搬过来
I just relocated from New York
他们说我得重考一遍
and they said I had to take a test again.
我80年代的时候去过纽约
I went to New York once in the '80s.
最鼎盛的时代
The heyday.
我跟父母被一个人拿着武士刀抢劫了
Parents and I got mugged by a guy with a samurai sword.
-也不是所有人都喜欢那儿  -这里右转
- It's not for everybody. - Let's have you make a right.
过了这个红灯 请靠边停车 做个三点转向
After this light let's have you pull over and make a K turn.
没问题
Okey-doke.
-所以 保罗 我成绩如何  -非常好
- So, Paul, how am I doing? - Excellent.
你显然经验丰富
It's obvious that you're an experienced driver.
-最近这些年轻人  -趴下
- Some of these kids-- - Get down!
我天啊 天啊 我中枪了
PAUL: Oh, God! Oh, God, I'm hit! Oh, God!
趴下
Stay down!
你在干什么 快停车
PAUL: What are you doing? Pull over!
天啊
Oh, God! Oh!
这是宝剑插入的声音
♪ That's the sound of the sword goin' in ♪
你会害死我们的
You're going to get us killed!
咔咔咔 咔咔咔
♪ Clack-clack, clack-a-clang clang ♪
这是枪炮挥舞的声音
♪ That's the sound of the gun goin' bang-bang ♪
突突突突
♪ Tukka-tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk-tukka ♪
这是无人机发动进攻的声音
♪ That's the sound of the drone button pusher ♪
亲娘嘞 你在干什么
Oh, God! What are you doing?
我得去医院 送我去医院
I need a hospital! Get me to a hospital!
-我需要去医院  -给我闭嘴
- I need a hos-- - Look! Shut the fuck up.
上帝耶稣玛利亚啊
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
我觉得我活不成了
I think I'm dying.
你不会死的
You're not dying,
你要是会死 这会儿早死了
if you were dying you'd already be dead.
-咱们在干嘛  -我记住了部分车牌
- What are you doing? - I got a partial plate.
-过来  -别 你会让我感染的
- Come here. - Stop! You're gonna infect it!
听我说 你啥都没看到
Listen, you didn't see anything Paul.
不许乱讲话
Nothing. Okay?
大家都事吧
OFFICER: Everybody okay?
-你没事吧  -下午好 警官
- You okay? - DWIGHT: Afternoon, officer.
所以你在参加路考
BURKE: So you're at the light
正在等红灯时
taking your driver's test, and then--
然后一辆车不知从哪窜出来
Someone comes out of nowhere
开始朝我们一顿乱射
and starts shooting at us from another car.
也没发生口角 就砰砰砰开始干
Unprovoked. Just, boom, boom, boom?
我已经说了26次了
Like I said 26 times before.
这辆车 牌子型号都没有吗
And this other car, no make, model or color?
太快了 没注意 你这儿有可乐吗
It happened so fast. Do you have a Coke?
稍等
In a minute.
我们在系统里查过你的名字
You know, we ran your name through the system.
那你一定知道我是狮子座
Then you know I'm a Leo.
您前科累累 曼菲雷迪先生
You've got a lot of priors, Mr. Manfredi.
那都是前科 我已经坐过牢了
Priors is the key word. I did my time.
但你在黑帮不是小人物 这是肯定的
You are no lightweight, that's for sure.
所以我会因差点中枪而被起诉吗
So, I might be charged with almost getting shot?
有这个罪名吗
'Cause I don't think that's a crime,
就算是俄克拉荷马都没有
even in Oklahoma.
给你录完口供就释放你
Once your statement's complete, we'll release you.
释放
"Release?"
-我是被关押了吗  -也不全是
- I'm being held? - Not necessarily.
我们只想听听你的说法
We just want to hear your version of things.
比如 你有没有什么仇家
Like, who it is might want you dead.
说实话
Honestly...
我觉得这个凶手
I think whoever did this
一定是跟我考官有仇
had it out for the driving instructor.
我感觉他应该挂过很多人
I got a feeling he failed a lot of people.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
伯克警官给我讲了事情经过 你没事吧
Officer Burke filled me in. You okay?
我驾考通过了 厉害吧
I passed my driving test, there is that.
恭喜
Congratulations.
讲真 你来这儿干嘛
Seriously, what are you doing here?
我从无线电里听到发生了枪击案
Came over the radio, there was a shooting,
他们提到了你的名字
they mentioned your name.
你知道你可以走了吧
You know you're free to go, right?
到底他么什么情况
MULRONEY: What the fuck's going on?
为什么烟酒火器管理局要掺和进来
Why is the ATF butting in?
跟你们聊得特开心
DWIGHT: Wonderful spending time with you.
有个更大的案子 他正在参与调查
He's part of a bigger investigation,
-我只能说到这儿了  -是不想说吧
- that's all I can say. - Can or will?
你知道
STACY: You know,
你没必要请我吃饭的
you didn't have to buy me dinner.
还是说你想
Or is this to make up
弥补我们上次的短暂相见
for the brevity of our last encounter?
你刚经历过枪击
Got a pretty good appetite
居然还胃口这么好
for someone who was just shot at.
如果每次有人想害我 我都吓得吃不下饭
If I stopped eating every time someone tried to hurt me
我早成骷髅了
I'd be a skeleton.
你大概知道是谁吗
You got any ideas?
谁会想害你
Who tried to hurt you?
你来鸟不拉屎的俄克拉荷马干嘛
What are you doing in Cow Pattie, Oklahoma?
为了惩恶扬善 保卫中西部啊
Stopping bad guys from blowing up our country.
昨天的爆炸案你也在吧
You were involved with that explosion yesterday,
那个造炸弹的家伙
- the guy with the bombs? - Mm-hmm.
-这工作挺让人难受的吧  -比卖保险强
- Tough day at the office? - Beats selling insurance.
看来咱俩都喜欢
Seems like both of us sought out careers
干出生入死的职业
with their share of tough days.
你觉得是为什么呢
Why do you think that is?
因为我俩够疯狂
Because we're both fucking crazy.
我天
Oh, man.
谢谢你终于点破主题了
Finally, someone addresses the elephant in the room.
所以你离开纽约来了这儿
So you left New York to come here?
之前也辗转过其他地方
I popped around a few places before.
911之前我在海关工作 被人招募了
I was in customs before 9/11, got recruited.
-来到了烟酒火药管理局  -然后你调来了塔尔萨
- Switched to ATF. - So you transferred to Tulsa?
不 我是被发配过来的
No, I was asked to leave.
-发配  -上头的命令
- Asked? - Ordered.
所以我带着自己的家当
So I packed up myself and my plants
和我的前夫爱德华就
and my now ex-husband Edward and...
我当时心理崩溃了
I basically lost my shit.
而且很显然
And apparently
塔尔萨是烟酒火器管理局众多的流放地之一
Tulsa is one of the ATF's many versions of Siberia.
别这样
Come on now.
任何人经历了911
9/11?
心理都会受到影响
It's not like everybody didn't lose their shit
其实跟911无关
- a little bit. - It wasn't 9/11, actually.
是之后的事
It was later.
911时
9/11...
我表现出色
I was a rockstar.
得过警察荣誉奖章
Police Meritorious Service Medal.
警察杰出服务奖章
Police Distinguished Service Medal.
深受同事喜爱
They loved me.
-然后出了萨利机长那事  -萨利
- And then Sully happened. - DWIGHT: Sully?
把飞机平稳降落在哈德逊河上的机长
The guy who landed the plane in the Hudson River?
我当时正在去上4点到12点的班
I was doing a 4 to 12. Headed into work.
走在12大道 就看到这架飞机
I was on 12th Ave and I saw this plane...
孤零零的飞过来 当时就想
it was flying solo and I thought...
还能是什么情况 又来了
"What else could it be? Here we go again."
-我就崩溃了  -有情可原
- I freaked out. - It's understandable.
做我们这行就不行
STACY: Not in my line of work.
在你们这行
What happens in your work...
如果有人情绪崩溃 让同伴暴露在
If someone loses their shit and puts their...
危险之中
associate,
那会怎么样
someone who counts on them at risk?
结果可能不堪设想
Probably wouldn't turn out so well.
还记得我们上一次见面
Do you remember the last time we were together?
你说
You said...
如果我被抓 你帮不了我
you couldn't help me if I got jammed up.
我能说啥呢 看来我不是个好探员
What can I say? I guess I'm shitty at my job.
咱们俩再也不能
This cannot and will not...
-也不会有下次了  -好的
- happen again, okay? - Okay.
你别笑
Stop smiling. No.
这鞋需要我帮忙吗
You need some help with this shoe?
不用 我能行 谢谢
No, I've got it. Thank you.
我可以帮你脱下来
I helped you get it off.
谢谢你请我吃饭
Thank you for dinner.
史黛西
DWIGHT: Stacy.
如果你找到了想杀我的人 就告诉我
Let me know if you find out who tried to shoot me.
突然接到你的电话 真开心
CHICKIE: What do I owe the pleasure?
我可开心不起来
DWIGHT: I think the pleasure might be one sided.
你什么意思
CHICKIE: What do you mean?
有人昨天想杀我
Somebody tried to kill me yesterday.
等等 什么
CHICKIE: Whoa, what?
我天哪 出什么事了
Get the fuck out. What happened?
这人趁我等红灯时
DWIGHT: Stopped at a light.
-二话不说开始射击  -谁干的
- Guy started shooting. - Who was it?
我还想问问你呢
I was hoping you could tell me.
我怎么会知道
How the fuck should I know?
我只会问一次
I'm going to ask you this one time
你最好跟我说实话
and you be straight with me.
是文斯的人干的吗
Is this Vince's hand?
我已经把各方矛盾摆平了
Hey, I mediated a fair outcome with all parties.
这件事已经翻篇了
The issue is dead.
所以你确定不是这个小杂种
DWIGHT: So you're telling me there's no chance
由于嘴里飙粪
of this punk going rogue
被我打断下巴
on account of me breaking his jaw
自己不服气寻仇的吗
because of his big fucking mouth?
他个傻逼说什么呢
What's he fucking saying?
你他妈别血口喷人
You know, you got some fucking balls,
-知道吗  -有吗
- you know that? - DWIGHT: Do I?
要是你在红绿灯被人偷袭
Let someone try to take you out at a stoplight
你头一个想到的会是谁
and we'll hear your list of suspects.
你什么意思
What are you referring?
我镇不住人吗
That I'm weak?
我带不好自己的队伍吗
That I can't control my own fucking crew?
我跟文斯说了 翻篇儿了 都过去了
I told Vince it's over. It's fucking over.
把你脆弱的自尊收好 齐齐
Fuck your bruised ego, Chickie,
袭击我的人是个带着滑雪面罩的
I got shot at by some ball-less sack of shit
-没种傻逼  -好的
- in a ski mask. - Okay.
我明白 好吧
I get it, all right?
但我已经回答过你的问题了
And I gave you my answer.
顺便一提
But by the way,
就算不论你跟我爹多年的交情
your lifelong friendship with my father aside
从商业决策的角度来看
just as a pure fucking business decision,
我得是疯了才会想杀你
I got to be out of my mind to take you out.
你多能赚钱啊
You're a great earner.
当然了 你说的对
Of course. What was I thinking?
那换我问你
Now let me ask you,
你是跑外头去树敌了还是什么
you make any enemies out there
是不是睡了别人老婆之类的
fucking some cowboys wife or something?
别侮辱我
Don't insult me.
那你自己去搞清楚 行吗
Well, you figure it out. Okay?
搞清楚了记得通知我 但你现在应该没事吧
You let me know. But you all right, though?
不然也不会来找我了
I mean, otherwise.
是啊 我是天选之人
Yeah, I'm blessed.
你他妈的可是有九条命呢
You with the nine fucking lives.
真是谢谢你帮我数着
DWIGHT: I'm glad somebody is counting.
替我向你父亲问个好
Give your father a kiss for me.
行
Yeah.
暂停
Stop.
这是基兰·沃尔特里普
That's Caolan Waltrip.
他是黑碎石帮的老大
He's the head of Black Macadam,
那是个非法的摩托帮
a one percenter motorcycle gang.
那天双方在那栋屋子僵持的时候
He showed up during the standoff at the house
他也来过
the other day.
不知道为什么 他还有他的手下
For some reason, he and his crew
突然开始全副武装了
are suddenly arming themselves to the teeth.
用致命武器袭击他人 谋杀未遂
Assault with a deadly weapon, attempted murder,
盗窃未遂 再是谋杀未遂
attempted larceny, attempted murder.
他在阿蒂卡监狱蹲了6年 重大持械抢劫罪
He did six years in Attica. Major armed robberies.
被放出来之后又重操旧业了
Got released and picked up where he left off.
这是埃德加·杜蒙特 沃尔特里普的前任狱友
Ooh, that is Edgar Dumont. Former cell made of Waltrip's.
就是把自己炸飞的那个疯子
He's the lunatic who blew himself up.
罗比·特鲁科特还有卡森·派克
Robbie Trucotte and Carson Pike.
任何人想接近沃尔特里普的身
Yeah, nobody gets within 20 feet of Waltrip
都得先过派克这一关
without going through Pike first.
这怪人又是谁
Who's this wacko?
这是通称罗克西的罗谢尔·哈灵顿
STACY: That is Rochelle "Roxy" Harrington.
她是个弹药专家
She's actually a munitions expert.
三次被派驻阿富汗 沃尔特里普很听她的
Did three tours in Afghanistan. She's got Waltrip's ear.
作为一个在犯罪集团里
Kinda thin file
地位这么高的人 她的前科好像不多
for someone moving that far up the food chain,
她估计打破了职业的天花板
She probably hit the glass ceiling.
现在杜蒙特死了
With Dumont out of the picture
我们应该优先调查这三个人
I think we focus on these three guys.
詹妮弗
JOHN: Jennifer?
你家屋顶呢
JENNIFER: How about your roof?
-你家屋顶吗  -说得好
JOHN: Your roof? CONTESTANT: Good answer!
-嗨 保罗  -曼菲雷迪先生
- Hello, Paul. - PAUL: Mr. Manfredi.
-您怎么来了  -我总得来看看你
- This is unexpected. - Hey, it's the least I can do.
电视节目为美国节目《家庭问答》 是团体智力答题游戏
瞧瞧你 这么多慰问品
Look at all these goodies.
-这我能用吗  -可以啊
- Okay if I use this? - I guess.
谢谢您
Thank you.
您真是太客气了 非常感谢
Not necessary, but very much appreciated.
不用跟我客气
Don't mention it.
所以警方知道是谁干的了吗
So, the police, do they know who did it?
他们没查到
They're coming up short.
他们缺人
They're understaffed.
我在想 或许你可以帮帮他们
I was thinking maybe you could help out.
-我吗  -对 保罗 你
- Me? - You, Paul. You.
对了 有东西要给你 是慰问卡
Got something for you. Get well card.
打开看看
Open it.
-这是什么  -我看着像是一万块
- What is this? - Looks like ten grand to me.
-什么一万块  -小声点
- $10,000? - Shh!
这是我该做的
This is the least I can do
给你补偿一下受的这些痛苦折磨
to compensate for your pain and suffering.
感觉我不应该收
I don't know, this seems wrong.
你会觉得不应该收
It only seems wrong
是因为你觉得自己不配
because you feel like you didn't earn it,
那我们就这样
so here is what we're going to do.
那是一辆蓝色的雪弗兰凯浦瑞丝
It was a blue Chevy Caprice.
这是车牌前4位数
These are the first four numbers on the plate.
我希望你能联系你在车管局的朋友
I want you to call your buddies down at the DMV
看看他们能不能查到些什么
and see what they come up with.
警方不是应该
Shouldn't the police--
我很为你骄傲 保罗
I'm proud of you, Paul.
说说看 如果你能自己修好就能帮你省下一大笔钱的
JOHN: Name something that you'd save a fortune on
-是什么东西  -这是重播集
- if you knew how to fix it. - It's a rerun.
-电视机可以吗  -你的电视机
- How about "television?" - JOHN: Your television.
说得好
CONTESTANT: Good answer!
-还有两个回答  -祝你早日康复
- JOHN: Two answers remain. - Feel better.
油都汽车旅馆
那什么玩意儿 巧克力豆曲奇吗
What's that, chocolate chip?
-这什么  -你的遣散费
- What's this? - Your severance.
你看见那辆车上的弹孔了吗
You see the bullet holes in that car?
还有碎掉的窗户
The missing windows
窗户后的本来会是你
where your head could have been?
我看到了
Yeah, I seen it.
我来不是为了害死你的
I'm not here to get you killed.
那辆车在你家门口停了一晚上
It's bad enough that thing was parked
这就够糟糕的了
in front of your house all night.
万一你妈妈 你姐妹
God forbid your mother, your sister,
或者是个路人经过
somebody walks by
-然后被误认成我  -听着 我明白你的意思 好吗
- and gets mistaken for me. - Look, I hear you, okay?
我只是想说 我愿意付出努力
I'm just saying that I'm willing to pay my dues.
什么努力
What dues?
我知道你觉得我是个游手好闲的混混
Look, I know you think I'm some punk ass bitch,
但我不是 我愿意努力证明自己
but I'm not, I'm willing to put the work in,
-只要你能给我个机会  -小孩 你听好
- just give me a chance. - Listen, kid.
我不是小孩了 我都25了 我什么都懂
I'm not a kid. I'm 25 years old. I get it.
这是你自己选的
This is your choice.
对
Fine.
你要我干什么
Now, what do you need?
首先 我需要一辆新车
First of all, I want a new car.
所以给我去找那个经销商
So go see that guy at the dealership.
没问题
Done.
不要林肯领航员 也不要黑色的车
And not a Navigator, and not black.
-我懂你意思  -而且得是免费的
- Oh, I get it. - And I want it for free.
-免费的 这什么意思  -那辆车是辆次品
- For free? What you mean? - That one's a lemon.
随随便便就能打穿
It's got bullet holes all over it.
犯罪现场 请勿进入
曼菲雷迪先生 我是塔尔萨车管局的
PAUL: Mr. Manfredi, this is Paul Cheevers
保罗·奇弗斯
from the Tulsa DMV.
你
The, um,
你要找的东西 是被塔尔萨卫生部门处理了
object you're looking for was dumped and tagged
目前被安置在
by Tulsa Sanitation
橡树大道和奥兰多大道附近的
at an abandoned lot
一个废弃停车场里
near Oak and Orlando.
不用给我回电话了 真不用了
No need to call back. Ever.
跟OJ辛普森一样 先戴上手套
Okay, OJ got on them Isotoners.
我懂
I see you.
火需要氧气才能烧起来
Fire needs oxygen to burn.
这蠢货把窗子都关死了
This idiot kept the windows closed.
-二甲基亚砜  -二甲基亚砜
- DMSO? - DMSO.
二甲基亚砜（DMSO）是一种含硫有机化合物 常温下为无色无臭的透明液体
是一种吸湿性的可燃液体 也被誉为“万能溶剂”
这是一种用于给马减轻炎症的
It's a liniment used to reduce inflammation
阵痛油
in horses.
高度易燃
It's highly flammable.
这什么 你看着像FR吗
What's that? Look like "FR" to you?
对 是FR
That's FR.
搜关键词FR加上马
DWIGHT: Type in "FR" and "horses."
离这里5英里开外
Place about five miles from here.
有个芬纳里奥牧场
Fennario Ranch.
你要去吗
So you want to go?
这次我自己去
I'm gonna do this alone.
-你们老板在吗  -应该在那边的马厩里
- Your boss around? - Check the stables out back.
打扰一下
DWIGHT: Excuse me.
是芬纳里奥太太吗
Mrs. Fennario?
是德弗罗小姐
Miss Devereaux.
芬纳里奥只是牧场的名字而已
Fennario is just the name of the ranch.
我还以为我们是同乡呢
See, that's me thinking you're a paisan.
我喜欢意大利美食 这能算吗
Well, I like Italian food. Does that count?
当然算了
Of course it does.
-有什么可以帮到你的吗 先生  -马可尼
- How can I help you, Mister-- - DWIGHT: Marconi.
我是个私家侦探
I'm a private investigator.
我的一个顾客 有人偷走了他的车 还给烧了
A client's car was stolen and set on fire,
这是我在后座上找到的东西
and I found this in the back seat.
这些玩意儿就是浪费钱
Ah, these things are a waste of money.
每次一买来就被偷
Get stolen as soon as I buy them.
-我还找到一罐二甲基亚砜  -所以呢
- Also found a can of DMSO. - Okay, so?
你觉得你们这儿会不会有员工
Do you think anybody working here
做出这种事呢
is capable of doing something like that?
-烧车吗  -对 还有开枪杀人
- Burning a car? - You know, or shooting somebody.
我不知道你是什么人 或者你想干什么
Like, I don't know who you are or what you want.
-我是个私家侦探  -我还是个宇航员呢 骗鬼去吧
- I'm a private investigator. - Right. And I'm an astronaut.
我这儿有171个员工
I employ 171 people.
我能保证他们在这里干活的时候只做正经事
I can vouch for the work ethic while they're here,
但他们一出这里大门
but once they're through those gates--
那你介意我到处打听打听吗
Well, do you mind if I ask around?
在我这儿吗
On my property?
-当然介意了  -也有道理
- Yeah, I do mind. - Fair enough.
-你还有别的事吗  -有
- Anything else? - DWIGHT: Yeah.
你们这儿有马术课吗
Do you give riding lessons?
打官网上的电话去
Call the number on the website.
我喜欢这个州
DWIGHT: I like this state.
你觉得你厉害了是吧
TYSON: You think you so badass, huh?
偷袭我兄弟
Run up on my boy?
还随便扫射
Take potshots?
悄悄跑过去埋伏袭击别人是吧
Sneak up and ambush some motherfucker?
你这就太蠢了
Oh, that's a bad move,
你知道的吧 我跟他
'Cause you, uh, you know me and him...
我们关系可铁了
we tight
We tight.
你对他下手
You make a move on him,
就等于对我下手
you best make a move on me, too.
你对他下手
You make a move on him...
就等于对我下手
You best make a move on me, too.
到处乱扫射一通
Coming in guns blazing.
我会杀了你的
I will kill you.
-你还好吗  -我捡了条狗
- How are you doing? - I got a dog.
流浪狗 年纪大了点 精力不旺盛
He's a stray. He's a little old and beat up.
看来你就好这一口
Well, somebody's got a type.
你等会儿有空过来吗
You around later?
抱歉 有事要办
DWIGHT: Sorry. Plans.
没事
Oh, that's okay.
你准备给狗起名叫什么
What are you naming the dog?
我想给他起名叫机会
I was thinking about naming him Chance.
是重新做人的机会 还是最后通牒的机会
As in second or last?
不知道 我还没想那么多
TBD. I haven't gotten that far yet.
我得挂了 有事及时找我
I gotta go. Keep me posted.
兄弟 我的小兄弟 你还好吗
ARMAND: Hey my man! My little man! How are you?
-好孩子 你还好吗  -快进来 爸
- How's my best boy? - TOMMY: Come on, Dad!
-好孩子 你还好吗  -我可好了
- ARMAND: How's my best boy? - TOMMY: I'm so great!
学校里今天怎么样
ARMAND: How was school today?
我人生的三分之一的时间都在坐牢
I went away for a third of my life
你还想杀我
and you try to shoot me?
我太太马上就回来了
My wife is going to be home any minute now.
我会给她留信的
I'll leave a note.
赶紧赚钱去
Go out there and make some money.
要来个气球吗
You guys want a balloon?
这里是我们的地盘
This is our territory.
这笑气就是我们的命根子
This nitro is our existence.
你读过《孙子兵法》吗
You ever read "The Art of War?"
-你说真的吗  -我已经想好了
- Really? - DWIGHT: I got a plan.
你会需要很多帮助的
You need all the friends you can get.
走吧 小伙子们
Let's go, my children.